<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.2//EN" "./dtd/document-v12.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>WebServices - Axis</title>
  </header>
  <body>

<a name="Bugs"/>
<section>
<title>WebServices - Axis - </title>

<p>New Axis bugs should be reported using <a href="http://issues.apache.org/jira">JIRA</a> (the Apache bug database).</p>

<ul>
  <li>Please report bugs against the newest release.</li>

  <li>If you're not sure whether the behavior in question is a bug or a feature, please post a message to the <a href="mailto:axis-dev@ws.apache.org">axis-dev</a> mailing list for clarification.</li>

  <li>To avoid duplicate bug reports, please query JIRA to see whether the bug has already been reported (and perhaps fixed).</li>

  <li>If you can't find your bug in the database, it would help if you could check out Axis from SVN, and build it locally to verify that the bug still exists.</li>

  <li>If you have found a new bug, please enter an Axis bug report in JIRA. Remember to include the following information:

    <ul>
      <li>Version number of Axis</li>

      <li>Version number of JDK (enter "java -fullversion")</li>

      <li>Instructions for how to reproduce the problem, ideally including a small testcase.</li>
    </ul>

    <p><i>Before you can enter your first bug report, you must submit your email address to JIRA and receive a password.</i></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Bugs related to WSDL4J should be addressed to the Expert Group for JSR110 at <a href="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/jsr110-eg-disc">http://groups.yahoo.com/group/jsr110-eg-disc</a>.</p>

<p>For more information visit the following links:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://issues.apache.org/jira/">Apache JIRA</a></li>
</ul>

<p>We also encourage you to write patches for problems you find and submit them to the <a href="mailto:axis-dev@ws.apache.org">axis-dev</a> mailing
list. If we agree the problem is a bug and the patch fixes it and does not break something else, we are likely to include the patch in the next release.</p>

</section>

  </body>
</document>
